We and our partners use technologies, such as cookies, to recognize you and show you more of what you like. Please read our [Privacy Policy](https://www.lomography.com/about/privacy) to learn more. By using this website you agree to the use of those technologies. [I agree.](https://www.lomography.com/)

* 

* 
* Hello
* More
* Lomography International Lomography Deutschland Lomography España Lomography France Lomography Italia Lomography 日本 Lomography 대한민국 Lomography ประเทศไทย Lomography Türkiye Lomography 台灣 Lomography 香港 Lomography Indonesia

Privacy Statement
=================

Welcome to LOMOGRAPHY! Lomographische GmbH, a Vienna-based private limited company, incorporated under Austrian Law, and/or its affiliates (“we”, “us”, “our”), provide Products and Services to you, subject to the following Privacy Policy. By visiting our Website(s) lomography.com (lomography.com or any domain under the “Lomography” brand with a different top-level domain, such as lomography.de) or by using our Services, you agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy. “You” means you, the visitor, or user of our Services. We are the data controller responsible for the processing of personal data in relation to the Products and Services provided.

**Please read this Privacy Policy carefully as it provides you with important information about how we collect, use, and protect your personal data. This Policy is an integral part of our Terms & Conditions and informs you on the major aspects of the data processing on our Websites.** By visiting our Websites and/or using our Services, you acknowledge that you have read and understood this Privacy Policy. We consider your use of our Website and/or Services as a freely given, specific, informed, and unambiguous consent to the processing of your personal data as described in this Policy. Feel free to contact us if you have any questions, using the contact details provided at the end of this Privacy Policy. We’re happy to help!

In order to visit our Websites and/or use our Services, it will be necessary for you to provide us with some personal data as outlined here. If you choose not to provide this information, you will not be able to visit our Websites and/or use our Services.

We will retain your data only for as long as is necessary to provide the Products and Services outlined in this Privacy Policy or as required by applicable laws and regulations. Once your data is no longer needed for the purposes for which it was collected, we will securely delete or anonymise it in accordance with our data retention policies.

The processing of personal data is carried out in accordance with the provisions of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and applicable national data protection laws, such as the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA) for individuals residing in California, or the revised Swiss Data Protection Law. Our legal basis for processing your personal data is Art. 6 (1) (a) (consent), (b) (necessary for the performance of a contract), and/or (c) (legal obligation) of the GDPR. Additionally, we may process your personal data based on our legitimate interests as outlined in Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR. These legitimate interests include ensuring the security and integrity of our systems and services, conducting fraud prevention, and improving our Products and Services. Personal data may be processed in the European Union or in countries outside the EU/EEA, such as Switzerland or the United States, subject to appropriate safeguards under GDPR Article 46, such as standard contractual clauses, or adherence to approved data privacy frameworks. Please note that we may also share data globally within our group of companies under the appropriate safeguards and protections to maintain the security and confidentiality of your personal information.

We do not use any automated decision-making processes, including profiling, in our data processing activities. Therefore, you will not be subject to any decision based solely on automated processing that produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affects you.

To ensure your privacy, we invest in high-quality security and use the latest technology to protect your personal information. We take appropriate measures to prevent unauthorised access, disclosure, modification, or destruction of data. To ensure the secure transmission of your personal data, all transactions are processed using industry-standard 128-bit encryption. This robust encryption technology helps safeguard your data from unauthorised access and maintains the privacy and security of your personal information throughout its transmission and storage.

Your Rights
-----------

We will not disclose, share, or sell your personal information to third parties unless we have obtained your explicit consent or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties that we believe may be of interest to you, only if you have consented to receive such communications.

You have the right, at any time and free of charge, to access, rectify, erase, restrict processing, object to processing, and data portability regarding your personal data as provided under the GDPR or other applicable national data protection laws. If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact us! Additionally, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if you believe your rights have been violated. We are committed to responding to any such request within a reasonable timeframe and in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

Your Responsibilities for Personal Data of Third Parties and IT Security
------------------------------------------------------------------------

Please note that any content posted or information shared by you on our Community Websites may be publicly accessible and subject to editing at our discretion! As a user of our Services, you are responsible for ensuring that any personal data of third parties obtained, published, or shared through our Services complies with applicable data protection laws. You must have the necessary legal basis, such as explicit consent, to process such data. We are not responsible for any violations of data protection laws by our users.

By using our Websites, you acknowledge that any form of web scraping or crawling, including the use of automated bots, software, or any other means to extract, collect, or scrape data from our Website, is strictly prohibited without obtaining our explicit consent, as such activities may involve the processing of personal data and are subject to compliance with the GDPR.

We take measures to protect the security of our Website and your personal data, but ultimately, it is your responsibility to ensure the security of your own devices and internet connection. We recommend that you follow all IT security best practices, such as using strong passwords and keeping your software up to date.

Storage and Processing of Postings and IP Addresses
---------------------------------------------------

We collect and store your assigned IP address for necessary operation of our Websites, as well as for security reasons in case of any violation of third-party rights or unlawful content. An IP address is a unique series of numbers that identifies your device, such as a computer or smartphone, when it connects to the internet. Along with your postings, we store and publish additional information such as date, time, and pseudonym.

Furthermore, for the purposes of operation, error tracking, and maintenance, we may collect and process system logs and IP addresses during specific maintenance periods. We ensure that this data is processed in compliance with applicable data protection laws and deleted or anonymised when it is no longer necessary for these purposes.

Use of Aggregated Demographic Information for Analytical or Statistical Purposes
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

We may use aggregated demographic information provided by users for analytical or statistical purposes. This information will not contain any personal data that can identify individual users. We will ensure that your privacy rights are protected, and we will not distribute any information that could identify you.

Analytics, Cookies, and Tracking Pixels
---------------------------------------

We use analytics, cookies, and tracking pixels on our site to enhance your experience and improve our services. By continuing to use our site, you are providing your consent to the use of these technologies. Personal data from analytics, cookies, and tracking pixels will only be deleted upon your request. Without a request from you, we consider your continued use of our site as consent for the use of those technologies. However, you have the right to withdraw your consent and request deletion of your personal data at any time. Please contact us to make such a request. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe and in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

**What are analytics?** We use analytics to gather and analyse data to gain insights into patterns, trends, and behaviours. This data helps us understand how you interact with our Websites and Services, identify areas for improvement, optimise our marketing campaigns, and make data-driven decisions. Analytics provides valuable insights into how users find and use our Websites and Services, which pages or features are most popular, and how different marketing channels perform. By leveraging analytics data, we can improve our Websites, user experience, and overall performance.

We collect your IP address for Google Analytics in pseudonymous form, which is a non-precise information related to your geography and derived from the truncated IP address of your connection. It will be processed by Google Ireland Limited, located at Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, in accordance with their [privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy), and collected in order to serve you ads only for products and services available at your location. Google Analytics does provide coarse geo-location data by deriving the following metadata from IP addresses: city (and the derived latitude and longitude of the city), continent, country, region, subcontinent (and alphanumeric codes assigned). For EU-based traffic, IP-address data is used solely for geo-location data derivation before being immediately discarded. It is not logged, accessible, or used for any additional use cases.

**What are Cookies?** Our Websites use cookies to enhance your experience. Like almost all professional websites, we use cookies, which are small text files downloaded by your browser to your device. Don’t worry, it’s safe! Cookies do not cause any harm to your device and do not contain viruses. We or our third-party service providers may use cookies to identify users and remember their preferences.

We use cookies to remember when you are logged into our website, so you don’t have to log in again every time you visit a new page. These cookies are necessary for providing you with access to certain features and areas of our website that are restricted to logged-in users. When you log out, we typically remove or clear these cookies to ensure that you can only access restricted features and areas when you’re logged in again. However, please note that in some cases, these cookies may remain on your device even after you log out, until you manually remove them.

When you create an account with us, we will use cookies to manage the sign-up process and to assist with general administration tasks. Additionally, we use traffic log cookies to identify which pages on our website are being used by visitors. This information helps us to analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website to better meet our customers’ needs. We only use this data for statistical analysis purposes and then remove it from our system.

Below is a list of the cookies we collect and the information they store:

* COOKIE\_CONSENT\_FOR\_LOMOGRAPHY: If the visitor has consented to our usage of cookies
* FIRST\_REQUEST: indicates if this is the first visit
* FIRST\_VISITED\_AT: when was the first visit of the visitor
* LAST\_VISITED\_AT: when was the last visit of the visitor
* VISITS\_COUNT: how many times did the visitor visit the site
* LOMOGRAPHY\_SSO\_SESSION\_ID: the current session id from our account server (only for logged in users)
* LOMOGRAPHY\_SSO\_TICKET\_ID: the current ticket id from our account server (only for logged in users)

To help us understand how you use our site and improve your experience, we use Google Analytics, which is a widely used analytics solution on the web. Through the use of cookies, we can track the duration of your visit and the pages you access. This information helps us to produce engaging content and make improvements to the site. Additionally, traffic audiences based on your past browsing and purchasing behaviour may be created and linked with Google Ads, a service that shows ads in search engine results and Google’s partner network. Please note that your data will be processed by Google Ireland Limited, located at Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, in accordance with their [privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

We respect your right to control your personal data, and you can prevent the setting of cookies by adjusting your browser settings (please see your browser’s help documentation for instructions). However, please note that disabling cookies may impact the functionality of our website and many other websites that you visit. Disabling cookies may also result in the disabling of certain features and functionalities on this site. Therefore, we recommend that you keep cookies enabled for the best possible experience when using our services.

**What are tracking pixels?** We also use tracking pixels, which are small graphics embedded in web pages that allow us to record and analyse log files. This helps us to perform statistical analysis and understand how visitors interact with our site. With tracking pixels, we can determine if and when our site was opened, and which links were clicked. This helps us analyse the flow of visitors on our website.

We use the Facebook Pixel, by Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2 Ireland, to track your interactions with our website. Please note that the Facebook Pixel collects your full IP address with each call-up of our site. However, any customer data you pass through the Facebook Pixel is hashed locally on the browser before it goes to the Facebook servers for matching. This hashing process turns your data into short encrypted messages that cannot be tampered with. Facebook uses these hashes to match pixel events with people on Facebook. Then Facebook deletes all matched and unmatched hashes immediately after the matching process ends. They do not collect or store any personally identifiable information on their servers. The Facebook Pixel uses secure https connection, so that any data transmitted from the browser will make it to their servers safely. By using our website, you consent to the processing of your data by Facebook in the manner and for the purposes outlined above in accordance with Meta’s [privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/policy/).

When Contacting Us
------------------

When you contact us through our contact forms or directly by email, we collect and store the data you provide for the purpose of processing your enquiry and any follow-up questions you may have. We keep this information for a maximum of six months, after which it will be securely deleted. We will not disclose any individual user details, including your email address, to any third parties without your prior consent, unless we are legally required to do so.

Newsletters
-----------

If you would like to receive our newsletter, you can subscribe on our website by providing us with your email address and consent to receive the newsletter. Once you subscribe, we will send you an email with a link to confirm your subscription. If you make a purchase on our website, we may send targeted newsletters for marketing campaigns that are specifically relevant to you and based on your jurisdiction.

You can unsubscribe from our newsletter at any time by sending a cancellation request to [help@lomography.com](mailto:help@lomography.com) or using the unsubscribe button at the footer of our newsletter. Once we receive your request, we will promptly delete your personal data related to the newsletter.

We respect your privacy and will not share your email address or other personal information with third parties without your prior consent.

Email Communication
-------------------

We use Gmail to send, receive and reply to emails. By sending us an email, you acknowledge and agree that your personal data, including your email address and any other information you provide, will be processed by Google Ireland Limited, located at Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, in accordance with their [privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy). We will protect your personal data and use it solely for the purpose of sending and responding to your email.

If you create an account on our website, we may contact you via email with information or queries related to your registration, subscription account, postings, reminders, follow-ups on products, warnings, or copyright requests. We may also send a reminder if you have items in your cart that you have not yet checked out.

If you do not wish to receive emails from us, you can adjust your preferences in the Email Preferences section of your User Profile or follow the instructions included in any unwanted email message. However, please be aware that you will still receive system emails (such as those regarding forgotten passwords) and legal notices (such as updates to our policies) from us.

If you make a purchase on our website, we may use your email address to create custom targeted audiences on Facebook, by Meta Platforms Ireland Limited, 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2 Ireland. We will not share your email address with any other third-party partner without your prior consent, and you will not receive unsolicited marketing emails from them. The email lists we provide to Facebook are hashed to convert your data into short encrypted messages that cannot be altered. Facebook does not collect or store any email information on their servers.

If you do not want to receive marketing emails, please let us know and we will promptly remove your information. If you wish to opt-out of future advertising campaigns from us, you can adjust your preferences in your [Facebook account ads preferences](https://www.facebook.com/ads/preferences/?entry_product%3Deducation_page).

Recruitment Data Protection Compliance
--------------------------------------

We process applications and other employment-related data solely for recruitment purposes and we do not share it with any third parties except our HR service provider Recruitee B.V., Keizersgracht 313, 1016 EE Amsterdam, The Netherlands, in accordance with their [privacy policy](https://recruitee.com/privacy-policy).

In accordance with the Equal Treatment Act (GlBG), we delete this data six months after filling our vacancies. While we cannot estimate the exact time until a vacancy is filled, we consider this period over when a candidate accepts our offer for the position for which we are considering you. Afterwards, we will either delete your data or ask you if we may keep it in our database for potential future roles.

Additional Third-Party Personal Data Collection and Processing
--------------------------------------------------------------

Please be aware that our service providers may collect and process additional data in accordance with their own privacy policies. We recommend that you review the privacy policies of these service providers to understand how they collect, use, and protect your personal data. We are committed to complying with the GDPR and other applicable data protection laws, and we will ensure that any data sharing with our service providers is done in compliance with these laws.

The data we collect is stored on the servers of our hosting service provider, Hetzner Online GmbH, located at Industriestr. 25, 91710 Gunzenhausen, Germany. They provide the necessary hardware, software, and network infrastructure to ensure the data is reliably stored, protected from unauthorised access, and accessible when needed. Please note that Hetzner Online GmbH is [committed to complying with GDPR regulations](https://www.hetzner.com/legal/privacy-policy) and maintaining the highest level of security for your data.

Additionally, we maintain necessary backups of the data, which are securely stored by Amazon Web Services EMEA SARL, 38 Avenue John F. Kennedy, L-1855, Luxembourg, in accordance with their [privacy policy](https://aws.amazon.com/privacy/).

In order to ensure the spatial distribution, high availability, and optimal performance of our services, we utilise a content delivery network (CDN) called KeyCDN, which is provided by proinity LLC, located at Ruemikerstrasse 60, CH-8409 Winterthur, Switzerland, in accordance with its [privacy policy](https://www.keycdn.com/privacy). By using this CDN, we enhance the user experience by delivering our content efficiently and effectively to you. This includes the distribution of our Services across various geographic locations, resulting in improved accessibility and faster loading times. KeyCDN is committed to compliance with the GDPR and its privacy team is continually reviewing features and practices to ensure GDPR compliance.

We use fonts provided by Hoefler & Co. for our Website, located at 611 Broadway, Room 725, New York, NY 10012-2608, USA, in accordance with their [privacy policy](https://www.typography.com/home/privacy.php).

Use of Integrated Components on Our Website
-------------------------------------------

When you visit our website, we may use integrated components (embeds) to enhance your browsing experience. When you access a page with an embedded component, your browser will automatically download and display it. During this process, the provider of the component may collect information such as the specific sub-page of our website visited and your IP address. We have integrated (embedded):

* YouTube; YouTube, LLC 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA; in accordance with their [privacy policy](https://www.youtube.com/static?template%3Dprivacy_guidelines) and [opt-out](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922).
* Vimeo; Vimeo, Inc., 555 West 18th Street, New York, New York 10011, USA; in accordance with their [privacy policy](https://vimeo.com/privacy) and [opt-out](https://vimeo.com/opt_out).
* Soundcloud; SoundCloud Limited, Rheinsberger Str. 76/77, 10115 Berlin, Germany; in accordance with their [privacy policy and opt-out](https://soundcloud.com/pages/privacy).
* Giphy; Giphy, 416 W. 13th Street, Suite 207, New York, NY 10014, USA; in accordance with their [privacy policy and opt-out](https://giphy.com/privacy).

We ensure that any use of integrated components is in compliance with applicable data protection laws, and we take steps to protect your privacy rights.

Use of Social Media Sharing Functionality
-----------------------------------------

We provide social media sharing buttons on our site, which allow you to connect with your social network and other services in various ways. Please note that these buttons are links to other services that do not compromise your privacy without your intervention. However, we cannot influence the data retrieved by these services if you follow these links or activate plugins by clicking on them. By clicking on these buttons, social media companies may collect your IP address, browser type, operating system, and other information related to your usage. They may also set cookies on your device, which can be used to enhance your profile on their site or contribute to the data they hold for various purposes outlined in their respective privacy policies. Please refer to the privacy policies of these social media services for more information on how they collect, process, and protect your personal data.

Links to/from other Sites
-------------------------

Any links to external resources, online services, or websites are provided for your convenience and to enhance the information available in our Services or on our Websites. Please be aware that when you visit external resources, online services, or websites that we may link to, your personal information may be subject to their own privacy policies, which may differ from ours. As such, we cannot guarantee the protection and privacy of any information that you provide while visiting such sites, and we advise you to review their respective privacy policies carefully before using them. Please note that such sites are not governed by this Privacy Policy and that we cannot be held responsible for any issues that may arise from their use.

Data Breach Reporting
---------------------

One crucial aspect of our compliance is promptly reporting any data breaches that may occur. Under the GDPR, we are legally obligated to report data breaches to the appropriate authorities within 72 hours of becoming aware of the breach.

Contacting our Data Protection Officer
--------------------------------------

If you wish to exercise your rights under the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) or have any questions or concerns about our data processing practices, please contact our data protection officer (DPO) using the contact information provided below:

Lomographische GmbH  
Kaiserstraße 34/12  
1070 Vienna, Austria  
Phone: +43-1-899440  

We are committed to responding to any such request within a reasonable timeframe and in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

Changes
-------

We are committed to keeping our Privacy Policy up-to-date and may amend it from time to time at our sole discretion. Your continued use of our Websites or Services after any modifications to this Privacy Policy shall constitute your acceptance of the updated Privacy Policy. If we make any material changes to the Privacy Policy, we will notify you by email or by posting a notice on our website prior to the effective date of the changes. It is important that you read the updated Privacy Policy and understand what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, it is disclosed. If you have any questions or concerns about the changes, please contact us.

This Privacy Policy is effective as of 1 June 2023.

Language Information (文A)
-------------------------

We can provide a non-binding translation to your language where needed.  
我們可以在需要時提供不具約束力的翻譯。我们可以在需要时提供不具约束力的翻译。  
Podemos proporcionar una traducción no vinculante cuando sea necesario.  
Nous pouvons fournir une traduction sans valeur légale si nécessaire.  
Bei Bedarf bieten wir auch gerne eine unverbindliche Arbeitsübersetzung an.  
Se necessario, possiamo fornire una traduzione non certificata e non vincolante.  
必要に応じて、拘束力のない翻訳を提供することができます。

##### Languages

You’re currently viewing this page in English. You can change your language preferences any time you like — just select your language from the dropdown list!

Lomography International Lomography Deutschland Lomography España Lomography France Lomography Italia Lomography 日本 Lomography 대한민국 Lomography ประเทศไทย Lomography Türkiye Lomography 台灣 Lomography 香港 Lomography Indonesia

##### Newsletter

Keep up to date with all things Lomography! Subscribe to our newsletter and be the first to know about amazing deals, brand new products, and essential creative photography news.

   Subscribe

##### Find our Products

##### Browse our Photos

##### Magazine

##### Join our Competitions

##### About Us

##### Explore our Channels

##### Got any questions?

##### Find us elsewhere

© Lomography 1994–2024
